In this lesson, we'll review a few technical details about the basic processes of a society, and this
will prepare us for the next lessons where we carry out the implementation.
So in this briefing, we'll review a bit more about Kuti as well as the basics of a WC Iot authentication.
And we'll also take a look at mutual TLS or MTA less for short.
And then we'll take a look at a WC security in touch on the device certificates and keys.
And that will lead us into the WC Iot policies, which will then segway us into JSON.
So let's dive right in.
Okay, now back to empty.
Empty stands for MQ Telemetry Transport.
And again, it's a simple lightweight messaging protocol designed for resource constrained devices on
constrained networks.
And muted is the standard for Iot messaging.
And it's used because it requires minimal resources and network bandwidth while ensuring reliability
and some degree of delivery assurance.
And this is what makes mq t ideal in machine to machine or internet of Things connected devices where
both bandwidth and battery power can be limited.
So MQ t uses a client server model where every Iot device is a client and is connected to a server called
an NQT broker, like an AWB Stewart, for example.
So in this model, clients send messages to an address called a topic.
Then the MQ broker will forward that message to all clients subscribed to that topic.
For example, here we have Thing X which publishes the lead on status to the lead topic.
The MQ broker then forwards the lead on status message to the thing y and things.
The clients which are both subscribed to the lead topic.
Okay.
Now let's take a look at a WSI Iot device authentication basics, a WC Iot devices authenticated using
mutual TLS authentication with x509 certificates and then cryptography x509 is an International Telecommunication
Union standard defining the format of public key certificates.
So once the certificate is provisioned inactivated, it can be installed on a device.
The device will then use that certificate for all requests to a society and we're going to generate
the required certificates in a WC and embed them into the ESP 32 in the next lesson.
Now let's cover mutual TLS MTA.
Less is used to establish trust between two parties and ensures that the parties at each end of the
network are who they claim to be.
By verifying that they both have the correct private key and the information in their respective TLS
certificates provides additional verification.
And we see later that we did what's called a root certificate, authority certificate, and the root
TLS certificate is necessary for MTA less, and this enables an organization to be their own certificate
authority.
The certificates used by authorized clients and servers have to correspond to the root certificate,
and this root certificate is self signed, meaning that the organization creates it themselves.
And again, in the next lesson we'll download the root CAA directly from a WC.
And in the case of a WC, they provide the device certificates and keys as A.W. as the certificate authority
for Iot devices.
So in this scenario, the certificates and keys are installed on the device and the device will use
that certificate and key to authenticate itself with a society.
Additionally, in this scenario, to perform a WSOP operations with your device, you must create an
AWG Iot policy and attach it to your device certificate and we'll go through this process in the next
lesson.
Now let's discuss the policies so about the US Iot policies.
These policies are JSON documents that authorize your device for performing AWG Iot operations.
IWC IOT defines a set of policy actions describing the operations and resources for which you can grant
or deny access.
And here are just a couple of examples.
Iot Connect represents permission to connect to an Iot message broker and Iot subscribe represents permission
to connect to an empty topic or topic filter.
So the policy document is in JSON or JavaScript object notation, which is an open standard lightweight
data interchange format.
And as a text document, it's easier for users to read and write and for machines to parse and generate.
And we'll also do this in the next lesson, but we don't have to create the JSON policy document manually.
We'll use the builder here and allow each action to then.
Okay.
So let's continue in the next lesson.